In this lecture, we're going to look at the 8th architecture
consideration that you need to think about when you're building
production grade, rag application.
And that is rag observability and monitoring.
So in better of knowledge basis, there are two types of logging
available.
One is the ingestion logs, and the second is the resource logs,
and both are published to CloudWatch.
Now, let's take a look at the ingestion logs.
And this focuses on, did we load the knowledge correctly?
So the ingestion logs record.
What happens when the data is added or updated in knowledge
basis?
So ingestion logs record.
What happens when the data is added or updated in a knowledge
base?
Document ingestion start, completion, chunking operations,
and embedding generation.
In one of the previous lectures, we had discussed about the
ingestion pipeline and the various steps in ingestion pipeline.
Loading the data, then chunking the data, creating vector
embeddings, and so on.
So for each of these better knowledge basis, create certain jobs.
And those jobs are monitored through this ingestion logging.
You'll be able to see the logs for each of the steps in the
ingestion pipeline.
The next, we have the resource logging that is more focused on
how is the knowledge basis being queried and used.
So logs record runtime usage of the knowledge basis.
So earlier, we had discussed about retrieve APA calls and retrieve
and generate APA calls.
So it can monitor both of them.
Then it can also monitor some of the request metadata like
time-staffed knowledge base ID that logs are being generated for.
And then finally, it will also log the response status, whether
to the user query, if the response had succeeded or failed.